<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lukasschirren.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://lukasschirren.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-04T14:50:28+00:00</updated><id>https://lukasschirren.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">A website to visualise the results from my master thesis</title><link href="https://lukasschirren.github.io/blog/2025/Hydrogen-in-Laos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A website to visualise the results from my master thesis"/><published>2025-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lukasschirren.github.io/blog/2025/Hydrogen%20in%20Laos</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lukasschirren.github.io/blog/2025/Hydrogen-in-Laos/"><![CDATA[<p>Last year, I completed my <a href="https://zenodo.org/records/13897880">master’s thesis</a> and subsequently spent the next several months preparing it for publication. This process primarily involved enhancing the content and conducting further analyses that were beyond my initial thesis work, such as examining electricity demand and runoff variability.</p> <p>Prior to my trip to Laos for the presentation for the Ministry of Energy and Mines, I sought a more intuitive method to present the different scenarios and devoted a few days to developing a Streamlit website for visualization. Check it out: <a href="https://greenhydrogen-laos.streamlit.app/">Green Hydrogen Laos</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="toc"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thesis topic was spatial-temporal optimisation for green hydrogen production]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Episode 7 - Navigating Global Energy Shifts | Energy Futures Lab | Imperial College London</title><link href="https://lukasschirren.github.io/blog/2024/episode-7-navigating-global-energy-shifts-energy-futures-lab-imperial-college-london/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Episode 7 - Navigating Global Energy Shifts | Energy Futures Lab | Imperial College London"/><published>2024-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lukasschirren.github.io/blog/2024/episode-7---navigating-global-energy-shifts--energy-futures-lab--imperial-college-london</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lukasschirren.github.io/blog/2024/episode-7-navigating-global-energy-shifts-energy-futures-lab-imperial-college-london/"><![CDATA[<p>In this section  In this episode of the Energy Futures Podcast, Lukas Schirren sits down with Dr. Yousef Alshammari, an award-winning energy analyst and founder of CMarkits, to explore the global changes influencing energy markets. From the impact of COVID-19 and geopolitical events to the evolving roles of fossil fuels and renewables, Dr. Alshammari provides insights into navigating today’s energy challenges and working toward a sustainable future.Tune in to learn about the key forces shaping the energy landscape, the role of natural gas as a transition fuel, and how AI and digitalization are paving the way for energy systems of tomorrow. with timestampsDr. Yousef Alshammari is the founder and CEO of CMarkits, with a background in energy analysis and consulting for OPEC and UNECE. His work focuses on sustainable energy solutions, and he’s known for his forward-thinking approach to decarbonisation. Connect with Dr. Alshammari on LinkedInTo deepen your understanding of the topics discussed in this episode, explore the following resources: Stay informed about the latest advancements in clean energy by subscribing to the Energy Futures Podcast on your preferred platform: Follow us for the latest updates on energy research, innovation, and policy: Discover more episodes of the Energy Futures Podcast, where we bring together leading voices in energy to discuss the science, technology, and policies driving the clean energy revolution.  Imperial College London South Kensington Campus London SW7 2AZ, UK tel: +44 (0)20 7589 5111 © 2025 Imperial College London</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>